Guide to the Laurence MacDaniels papers, [ca. 1915]-1986.
Laurence MacDaniels papers,
- Soil Analyses - 1952, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Soil analyses of 422 Chestnut Street for Lilium
- Remarks - 20 Year Dinner - May 22, 1956, 1956-05-22 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Copy of "Remarks" and related correspondence
- Monkey Run Nut Planting - Notes, Letters, Maps 1934-36, 1945, 1934-1945 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Christmas Carols - Words, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Numerous copies of non-Christmas song
- Map to Find 422 Chestnut St., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Invitation and map to, 1953
- Miscellaneous, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Copy of "A Typographical Error" and maps to 422 Chestnut St.
- L.H. MacDaniels - Index Rerun; Songs, Etc. Permanent File (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Hand written words to many songs
- Philosophical Paper, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Including correspondence with daughter Ellen; reprints of various philosophical articles including L.H.M. "Some Social Implications of the Scientific Method," 1940; and "Oncoming Changes in the Organization of American Public Education," E.E. Day; hand written notes; copy of Manuscript - "Social Implications... "
- Philosophical Article, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Hand written notes, rough outlines, correspondence
- B.P. Bishop Museum - 1939-1956 (not chronological), 1939-1956 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Correspondence and galley sheets to banana study
- Organic Gardening - Source Material, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 26)
  Many bulletins and correspondence regarding organic gardening, including J.I. Rodale; manuscript of L.H.M. "Organic Gardening - Fact, Fancy or Fraud"
- Time of Exposure and Other Photomicrographic Notes, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Poppy - Explaining(?) Poppy Storage, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous Maps - Personal, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  Including correspondence with R.T. Clausen 1942
- Pome Morphology Correspondence 1939-40, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Walnut Toxicity 1939-40, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  Notes and correspondence including letter from Joseph H. Bain to Wm. G. Buxby dated Oct. 17, 1919 regarding squirrel problem in Haddonfield, New Jersey
- L.H. MacDaniels - A Study of Pollen Germination Upon Stigmas of Apple Flowers Treated with Fungicides, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Manuscript 1939 American Society for Horticultural Science - Notes and photos
- Anatomical Technique, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  Paper: Experiments in Microbiology presented to American Association for the Advancement of Science 1940
- Nut Manuscript November 1943, 1943-11 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  Hand written notes and correspondence regarding black walnut, etc., including manuscript "Further Tests with Black Walnut Varieties," L.H.M. and J.E. Wilde 1943
- N. Ringing, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 35)
  Reprints and manuscript regarding pomological material and notes
- Personal Research - Hickory Study Old Material, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 36)
  Maps
- Notes - Photos of Apple Wood, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Single Pore Vessel Notes, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Notes - Winter Injury (?), Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Avery L. Skutt - Correspondence and Records 1942, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- L.H. MacDaniels - Adventitious Bud Research Notes, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Winter Injury 1934 - Hitchinqs, Beak, Jones Orchards Champlain Valley, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  Field notes
- L.H. MacDaniels Pollination Notes - 1938, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Sterility Studies - Cortland X E. McIntosh - Grimes X Arkansas - H. Terami 1936, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Winter Injury - Spring 1934 Western NY, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Winter Injury Notes - 1934 - C.U. Orchard and General, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- Autochrome Record Winter Injury 1934, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  Notes
- Work to be Completed, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  Including correspondence with G.P. Scoville 1940
- Adventitious Bud Study L.H. MacDaniels Research Notes, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 49)
  Includes copies of manuscript
- Yield Records Skutt Orchards - L.H. MacDaniels Fall 1935, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Skutt Orchard Yields 1933, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- Skutt Orchard Yield Records - McIntosh 1931 / L.H. MacDaniels - Skutt Orchards - Yield Data 1932, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Skutt Orchards - Yields and Pollination Data 1930, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Literature - Phloem -Translation of Papers - A.S. Crafts, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Pollination Data 1933, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Commercial Hand Pollination Data 1931-1933, 1931-1933 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Effect of Bactericides on Set of Fruit 1938, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  Manuscript with Hildebrand and notes
- Winter Injury - Toxicity of Winter Injured Wood, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Winter Injury - 1934 - General Material and Project, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  Statement
- Apple Leaf Paper - Old Manuscript Notes, Date Unknown (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Nut Growing Extension 1956-57, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Bunch Disease Survey, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Northern Nut Growers Association questionnaire and responses
- Northern Nut Growers Association Carl Prell, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Correspondence 1956
- Holden Arboretum - 1957, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Correspondence with L.F. Lipp of Holden Arboretum et al - regarding nut tree planting at Holden Arboretum including report from Northern Nut Growers Association
- Lewis F. Lipp 1956, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Correspondence regarding arboretum business
- Holden Arboretum - H.L. Crane 1956, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Holden Arboretum - G.L. Slate 1956, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Dr. H.L. Crane - Northern Nut Growers Association General Correspondence 1956, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Arnold Arboretum - John Wister 1956-57, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Correspondence and notes on October '56 program of Arnold Arboretum, etc.
- L.H. MacDaniels - Nut Growing in Northeast States - Miscellaneous Letters and Notes 1940-42, 1940-1942 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Including correspondence with J. Russell Smith; D. Wyman with tree crops reference
- L.H. MacDaniels - Northern Nut Growers Association Program September 4-6. 1941 - Letters and Notes, 1941-09-04-1941-09-06 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Including correspondence with J. Russell Smith
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1956 Meeting, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Including correspondence with G.L. Slate
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1953 - Publications Committee, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Correspondence with G.L. Slate
- Scions - 1954, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Northern Nut Growers Association - Spencer Chase, 1952-1956 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Correspondence 1952-1956
- Gilbert Becker, 1943-1954 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Correspondence 1943-1954
- Michigan Nut Growers Association Contest 1954, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Correspondence; awards list; scoring schedules; notes; etc.
- Presidential Address - "The Forward Look," L.H. MacDaniels - 1952, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Retiring address, year end report
- Northern Nut Growers Association - Rochester Convention - L.H. MacDaniels, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 19)
- 1953 Year End Report Northern Nut Growers Association, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Northern Nut Growers Association - W.S. Clark, Jr., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Correspondence 1953
- Scion Wood - Spring 1952, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Nut Growers Current File 1951-56, 1951-1956 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Including correspondence with G.L. Slate; S.L. Emsweller; Carl Prell; et al and newsletters from Northern Nut Growers Association
- Northern Nut Growers Association - R.B. Best 1952-1953, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Northern Nut Growers Association, 1925-1956 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  General correspondence 1925-1956, including Spencer Chase; G.L. Slate
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1951-52 Programs and Miscellaneous, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- The Nutshell, 1947-1954 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  Various copies of Nutshell 1947-54
- Northern Nut Growers Association Carl Prell, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  Correspondence 1951-55
- H.L. Crane 1953-56, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  Notes and correspondence
- J.W. McKay - 1955-56, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- L.H. MacDaniels - Northern Nut Growers Association Secretary - J.C. McDaniel 1951-52, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- J.C. McDaniel 1947-56, 1947-1956 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- G.L. Slate Northern Nut Growers Association 1953-56, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Northern Nut Growers Association - Membership Drive 1952, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  Correspondence - regarding membership drive, etc.
- Northern Nut Growers Association Mr. R.B. Best,Vice President 1951, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  Correspondence with and regarding R.B. Best
- L.H. MacDaniels - Norther Nut Growers Association 1951-52 Committees, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- L.H. MacDaniels - Northern Nut Growers Association 1951-52, Directors, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  Correspondence; notes; memos, etc.
- C.A. Reed and H.S. Crane 1949, 1943-1949 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  Correspondence from 1943-49
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1953 Rochester Convention, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  Including photo of exhibit at State Fair 1953; correspondence and newsletters 1950-53
- Nut Culture 1954-56, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  Correspondence including C.F. Gortzig; Spencer Chase; W.G. Brierly
- Chestnuts 1953-1956, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  Correspondence regarding general chestnut culture
- Nut Tree Propagation, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 42)
  General information
- Northern Nut Growers Association - Exhibits - Older Material - State Fair Exhibit 1950-52, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- 1953 Scion Wood, 1945-1954 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Nut Exhibits - State Fair 1953 and Northern Nut Growers Association Letters - Northern Nut Growers Association Members 1951-53, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Northern Nut Growers Association Exhibition Material State Fair 1953 Fair Officials, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  Correspondence 1950-1953 and notes
- Hickory Testing, 1947-1956 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  Correspondence 1947-56 including testing schedules, etc.
- Butternut Testing 1949-56, 1949-1956 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  Correspondence and notes
- Walnut Testing 1939-56, 1939-1956 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  Correspondence, schedules, notes
- Persian Walnut, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  Correspondence 1953-55
- Scions 1951, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  Correspondence 1950-51
- Scoring Schedule for Black Walnuts, 1937-1941 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  Correspondence 1940-41 and Northern Nut Growers Association schedule 1937
- Nut Growing Bulletin Material 1948, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Nut Testing, 1936-1955 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  Correspondence 1947-55; memo from Cornell University 1936 Including S. Chase; J.C. McDaniel, et al
- Manuscripts Concerning Nuts - L.H. MacDaniels, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 55)
  Manuscript by L.H.M., C.A. Reed
- Scions - 1941-56, 1941-1956 (Box 7, Folder 56)
- Nut Nursery Survey Fall 1956, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Northern Nut Growers Association - Competitive Exhibits 1955-7, 1955-1957 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  Correspondence, notes, photos regarding competitive exhibits
- Nut Testing and Nut Varieties 1951-54, 1951-1954 (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Miscellaneous Nuts 1945-1946, 1945-1946 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  Correspondence and nursery lists
- Writing for the Wise Company Lilies and Nuts, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 61)
  Correspondence regarding publication; manuscript; galley sheets; hand written notes
- L.H. MacDaniels - Judging Schedule for Persian Walnuts - Gravatt 1956, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  Correspondence and schedule
- Northern Nut Growers Association - Answered Not Filed - 1956-57, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  Including J.C. McDaniel; H.L. Crane; S. Chase; G.F. Gravatt; C. Prell
- L.H. MacDaniels - Walnut Testing 1947, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Correspondence with J.R. Smith, etc., notes on testing schedules; copy manuscript "Winter Injury to Nut Trees in Ithaca, New York in the Fall and Winter of 1947-48," by L.H.M. and Damon Boynton
- Northern Nut Growers Proceedings 1945 Manuscript, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Includes various manuscripts "Where Do We Go From Here?" by L.H.M. and others by Northern Nut Growers Association members; correspondence with C.A. Reed, etc.
- Nut Growing - Breeding and New Varieties, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Correspondence with E.J. Schreiner of U.S. Forest Service
- Things of Science Northern Nut Growers Association, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Various correspondence with Plant Industry Station in Beltsville, Maryland - regarding Things of Science Project
- Northern Nut Growers 1950 Convention - Butternut Paper, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Includes various correspondence about miscellaneous nut culture, NNGA convention, etc; copy manuscript of "How About the Butternut," by L.H. MacD; various copies of "Nutshell" correspondence with G.L. Slate and H.F. Stoke regarding the nomination of LHM as President of Northern Nut Growers Association; notes and agenda for August 28-30 meeting 1950
- L.H. MacDaniels - Northern Nut Growers Association 1953 State Fair Exhibit Design and Working Notes, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Includes correspondence with G.L. Slate regarding Boston exhibit (1953); between G.L. Slate and Steve O'Rourk of Guayaquil, Ecuador regarding hickories; various newsletters from Northern Nut Growers Association 1952; various correspondence - regarding state fair and Rochester meeting 1953
- Northern Nut Growers Association Rochester Meeting 1953, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Northern Nut Growers Association - Paper on Walnut Embryo, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Walnut and Hickory Tests 1945, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Northern Nut Growers - Judging Standards and Committee Report 1937, 1947, 1948, 1937-1948 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Various correspondence regarding judging; notes, etc.; Spencer Chase, C.A. Reed, H.F. Stone, et al
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1947-48, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Nut Culture - Permanent, 1943-1949 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  Various correspondence 1943-49
- Northern Nut Growers Association Meeting Norris, Tennessee 1948, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Various correspondence regarding meeting, unrelated material including brochure of Tennessee Valley Authority, various manuscripts (not LHM)
- Current 1952 Northern Nut Growers Association Correspondence, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Northern Nut Growers Association 1951 General Correspondence, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- C.A. Reed, Beltsville, Maryland - General Nut Growing (Northern Nut Growers Association), Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Correspondence with C.A. Reed, et al.
- Walnut Testing 1945-46, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Copy manuscript "Tests of Black Walnut Varieties for Differences in Kernal Yields," by S.S. Atwood and LHM; field notes; correspondence including T.G. Zarger of Tennessee Valley Authority, et al
- Administration - Northern Nut Growers Association - C.A. Reed, 1945, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Abscission - 1957, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  Small envelope of prints - abscission of English Oak, July 1956
- L.H. MacDaniels Department of Floriculture - Miscellaneous Current Research Notes 1955, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  Notes and correspondence with A.L. Schipper, Editor regarding manuscript of L.H.M. about abscission in woody plants
- Histo-chemistry - Juglans, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 21)
  General history of histochemistry
- Rose Stocks - Graft Union Research 1957, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Rose Stocks Research-Photographs, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Rose Stocks - 1954, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  Notes and Loose material - Various bulletins including "Progress Report on America's #1 Tree Crop Farm," 1956; envelope - American Horticultural Council including correspondence, bulletins, committee lists, meeting minutes, etc. Large expanding folder containing correspondence and information on Arnold Arboretum Case, 1957.
- L.H. MacDaniels - North American Lily Society - Awards and Standards - 1953, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  Awards blanks; correspondence with various Horticultural Societies and Agriculture Experiment Stations.
- North American Lily Society Committees 1947-1950, 1947-1950 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  Correspondence and committee lists
- R.D. Rappleye 1949-50, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  Correspondence with R.D. Rappleye of University of Maryland Department of Botany - regarding North American Lily Society business
- F.L. Skinner 1949-50, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  Correspondence with F.L. Skinner of Manitoba, Canada regarding North American Lily Society
- Dr. E.F. Palmer - North American Lily Society - Society Officers 1947-54, 1947-1954 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  Correspondence with E.F. Palmer - regarding lily culture and North American Lily Society business
- North American Lily Society - Norma E. Pfeiffer, Secretary 1947-1949, 1947-1949 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  Correspondence with Mrs. Norma E. Pfeiffer of Boyce-Thompson Institute, Yonkers, NY regarding lily culture and North American Lily Society business; including lists of various officers of North American Lily Society (1947-9)
- North American Lily Society - Carl Grant Wilson - 1948-9, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Ralph M. Warner 1955, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  Correspondence with R.M. Warmer, regarding financial business of North American Lily Society
- North American Lily Society - Seed Distribution - Mrs. Rowell 1948-1956, 1948-1956 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  Correspondence with H.D. Sayer, and Mrs. W.A. Rowell regarding seed distribution
- Arno Nehrling - North American Lily Society 1947-1955, 1947-1955 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  Correspondence with Arno Nehrling of Massachusetts Horticultural Society regarding North American Lily Society business
- North American Lily Society Letters to Membership and Other Memos 1947-49, 1947-1949 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- North American Lily Society - Lily Manuscript, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 36)
  Letter to G.L. Slate, copy manuscript "A Dozen Ways to Grow Lilies," L.H.M.
- North American Lily Society - Board of Directors. Ries, Henry,deGraaff, Fox, Etc. 1941-49, 1941-1949 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  Correspondence with officers and Board of Directors members including Dr. S.L. Emsweller; Memo announcing official organization of North American Lily Society, 9 July '47; Mrs. M.J. Fox; etc
- North American Lily Society - Letters of Officers - 1948-55, 1948-1955 (Box 8, Folder 38)
- North American Lily Society - Monumental Press 1949, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  Correspondence with Monumental Printing Company et al, regarding printing of North American Lily Society yearbook
- North American Lily Society - Philip Brierley, Treasurer; Membership 1947-50, 1947-1950 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  Correspondence with Dr. Brierley regarding lily culture, North American Lily Society membership; membership lists, general North American Lily Society business
- North American Lily Society - Canadian Membership - Pamenter, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 41)
  Correspondence with W.E. Pamenter of Toronto [Canadian Lily Society] regarding Canadian group, as well as E.F. Palmer, V.H. Ries
- G.L. Slate, Editor North American Lily Society 1946-55, 1946-1955 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  Correspondence with G.L. Slate regarding Lily Yearbook and all aspects of publication and general lily culture
- North American Lily Society - Membership Lists - 1949-50 - Treasurer's Report, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 42)
- North American Lily Society Slide Collection (Mrs. Harris') 1948-49, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  Correspondence with Mrs. Helen C. Harris - regarding slide collection; as well as with R.B. Stubbs, and letter from J.H. Odell of New England Gladiolus Society to Dr. Slate [G. L. Slate]
- North American Lily Society Miscellaneous Correspondence 1947-54, 1947-1954 (Box 8, Folder 44)
- 1953 State Fair Lily Exhibit, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  Copy of manuscript "The North American Lily Society Exhibit receives First Prize of NYS Fair" by L.H.M., correspondence with E.F. Palmer, C.G. Wilson,Norma Pfeiffer, et al - regarding State Fair exhibit
- Lily Research and Manuscript., Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 46)
  Miscellaneous field notes, reprints of various articles and correspondence with F.P. McWhorter
- Lily Society - 1951 - Mosaic Indexing and Control, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  Correspondence with F.P. McWhorter of Oregon St. College; Philip Brierley, Beltsville, Maryland; reprint of Brierley article "Prevalence of Cucumber and Tulip Viruses in Lilies," (1940); price list from Stewart's Lily Garden - Oregon 1951
- North American Lily Society J.L. Tingle 1951-54, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  Correspondence with J.L. Tingle - regarding North American Lily Society business
- Lily Acquisitions 1951-54, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  Correspondence with various individuals - regarding lily acquisitions
- North American Lily Society - Robert D. Rappleye, Secretary 1950-54, 1950-1954 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  Correspondence with R.D. Rappleye regarding North American Lily Society business and lily culture
- F.L. Skinner 1950, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  Correspondence with F.L. Skinner of Manitoba regarding lily culture and bulk exchange
- R.N. Stewart 1945-1952, 1945-1952 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  Correspondence with R.N. Stewart regarding North American Lily Society business, mostly yearbooks and some culture
- E.F. Palmer 1951, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  Exchange between E.F. Palmer and L.H.M. - regarding trip to Vineland
- Norma E. Pfeiffer 1950-54, 1950-1954 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  Correspondence with N.E.Pfeiffer - regarding lily culture
- North American Lily Society - Rev. E. Rigby, Vice President 1950, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  Correspondence with (W? E?) Rigby of Ontario, regarding lily culture (and North American Lily Society) and bulb exchange
- Warren L. Inskip 1951-2, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  Correspondence regarding North American Lily Society business
- Lily Exhibit at State Fair 1950, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  Correspondence with S.L. Emsweller, Jan de Graaff, W.L. Inskip, F.L. Skinner, C.G. Wilson, Norma Pfeiffer, E.F. Palmer, G.L. Slate, et al - regarding State Fair exhibit
- Newsletters - North American Lily Society Beginning with vol. 4, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 58)
- North American Lily Society - 1949 Lily Show - Annual Meeting, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  Correspondence and notes regarding 1949 Show and Annual Meeting
- North American Lily Society - S.L. Emsweller - Older Material 1947-55, 1947-1955 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  Correspondence regarding North American Lily Society, American Horticultural Council (Society)
- North American Lily Society - Warren Inskip, President 1950, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  Correspondence regarding North American Lily Society business including 3rd Annual Show, etc.
- North American Lily Society - General Correspondence 1947-50, 1947-1950 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  Including W.L. Inskip, G.L. Slate, et al - regarding North American Lily Society business
- North American Lily Society Committees 1949-50, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  Correspondence including Kruger, Inskip, Harris, Preston, Henry, Lawrence, et al
- North American Lily Society - L.H. MacDaniels - Judging Schedule 1953, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  Notes and correspondence with J.C. Taylor, S.L. Emsweller, G.E. Holland, Sandy Best, Arno Nehrling, L.H.M. - regarding judging
- North American Lily Society - W.L. Fulmer 1954, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 65)
- Lily Society 1951 Show and Committees, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  Lily Society 1951 Show and Committees Including newsletters and correspondence with S.L. Emsweller, R.B. Farnham of Horticultural Society of New York, W. Inskip, R.D. Rappleye, J.C. Taylor, Jan de Graaff, Arno Nehrling, G.L. Slate, et al - regarding shows, judging and committees
- Lilies - Illustrations and Photographs / Transcript from Eighth Annual Meeting of Northern American Lily Society - bound (12-13 July 1955), 1955 (Box 9, Folder 1)